Team leader
队长
What are you doing?
你干嘛
Nothing.
没事
That's
这个
what has happened.
事情就是这么个事情
Because both of your teams
因为你们两个队
won
在昨天的比赛里
yesterday's competition.
都取得了胜利
And you did very well.
表现得非常优秀
So
所以呢
I give you a suggestion
我代表校方
on behalf of the university.
给你们一个建议啊
Combine the two teams
就是把你们两个队合并
to form a new school team
形成一个新的校队
and select suitable teammates.
挑选出合适的队友
What do you think?
你们觉得怎么样
No way!
不可能
We still hope you
还是希望老师
can reconsider it.
能够再考虑一下
After all, husky is
毕竟哈士奇跟狼
essentially different from wolf.
还是有本质上的区别的
Wolf.
狼
Excuse me.
不好意思啊
We're human.
我们是人类
Human needs to protect animals.
人类是需要保护动物
Dogs are our good friends
犬类是我们的好朋友
and so are wild animals,
野生动物也是
even if they like to bite.
哪怕它们爱咬人呢
I heard that a debate team
听说昨天有个辩论队
narrowly won the low-end competition yesterday.
打低端局还是险胜呢
My fellow debaters, if you spread rumors again,
对方辩友再造谣的话
beware of our malicious retaliation.
小心恶意报复哟
In fact, in the debate competition,
其实这个辩论比赛
whether it is a narrow victory
无论是险胜
or a big victory,
还是大胜
as long as you win,
其实只要赢了
it is called a complete victory, right?
那就叫完胜 对吧
Sir
老师
There's no problem
您这么说我们队
for you to say that about our team.
是没有问题的
As for them...
至于他们嘛
My fellow debater, do you
对方辩友是不是对
have any misunderstanding about the complete victory?
完胜有什么误解
I heard that it used to seem that someone
我听说之前好像有人
gave up the best debater
把最佳辩手
to others, right?
都拱手让人了是不是
Excuse me, I have to answer the phone.
那个 我接个电话啊
You guys talk about it
你们商量一下
and give me an answer later.
回来给我答复
Are you
你
the senior's girlfriend?
是学长的女朋友
Are you crazy?
你没事吧
Why do you fabricate arguments?
怎么还捏造论据呢
Who are you talking about?
说谁捏造呢
I'm talking about the person who asks the question.
谁问的问题我说谁
My fellow debater, please
请对方辩友
do not sidestep my question.
不要逃避我的问题
Are you
你到底是不是
the senior's girlfriend or not?
学长的女朋友
I'm not.
我不是
Is what you said credible?
你 你说不是就不是啊
Behave yourself.
你说话注意素质
Who are you talking about?
说谁没素质呢
Yin Nan
殷楠
There's no one opposite us,
咱们对面又没人
but why do I always hear
我怎么总听见
strange noises?
奇怪的声音
You're right.
是
No one.
没人
It's air.
都是空气
It's air that buys your university.
空气把你们学校收购了
What are you talking about?
说什么呢你
Bro, keep your public persona.
大哥 人设
Bro
大哥
Maybe I should make a pot of chrysanthemum tea
要不我给大家泡壶
to cool you off?
菊花茶降降火
We are not getting irritated.
我们没有火气呀
Bad-mannered people get irritated easily.
没素质才容易上火呢
Why are you everywhere?
怎么哪儿都有你呢
Loser.
失败者
What are you talking about?
你说什么呢
I'm talking about you.
说你呢
All right.
算了 算了
Why did you
那你为什么
go to a hotel room
为什么要跟学长
with the senior?
一起去开房间
Because we have no place to train.
那是我们没有地方训练
That's for training.
我们找地方训练用的
Dango
团子
Please be ambitious.
咱长点出息
Don't waste your time
别把时间放在这种
on such a bad person.
歪瓜裂枣身上
Who are you talking about?
你说谁歪瓜裂枣呢
I'm talking about you.
我就说你呢
Say it again.
你再说一句
How are your discussions going?
商量得怎么样了
Have you got the results yet?
有结果了吗
Our team of Western University of Science and Technology
我们西科大校队
disagrees with it.
不同意合并
Our team of DUFE
我们东财大校队
disagrees with it even more.
更不同意
Just in time.
那正好
I was just informed.
我刚刚接到通知
The university will hold an exhibition match
学校在下周
for your two teams
将给两个队
next week.
办一场表演赛
Who has the final say
谁赢了
depends on who wins.
校队的事情谁说了算
Do you agree?
大家有没有意见
Do you hear that?
听见了吗
After the match,
打完比赛之后
the school team will be ours.
校队就是我们的了
We agree.
我们没意见
We agree, too.
我们也没有意见
Well.
那行
Looking forward to your wonderful performance.
我期待这场精彩的比赛
Let's see who will win.
我们赛场上 定输赢
Ah.
哎
Why don't Xiaoyu and Yin Nan
小鱼和殷楠
get along well?
为什么那么不对付啊
Have you ever heard of a story called
你听说过一个故事叫作
Other People's Children?
别人家的孩子吗
Yes.
听过
It's an inspiring story.
这是个励志的故事
And I'm that kind of child.
我就是别人家的孩子
Ah.
哎
What happened?
到底有什么八卦
Tell me.
讲讲
They were neighbors
她们两个
when they were children.
小时候住对门
Xiaoyu's mother always
小鱼的妈妈老拿
takes Yin Nan as an example.
殷楠说事
She also enrolled them
还给她俩报了
in the same interest class.
同一个兴趣班
Miss, I've finished drawing.
老师 我画好了
I'm great, right?
我厉害吧
Yin Nan, you draw very well.
殷楠 你画得好棒啊
Great.
好啊
You get a lot of gifts.
你这么多礼物啊
I can barely hold them.
快拿不下了
That year,
那年
Xiaoyu finally
好不容易
got the first place
小鱼考了期末的
in the final exam.
全年级第一
She thought she defeated Yin Nan.
她以为她战胜了殷楠
It turned out that
结果没想到
Yin Nan skipped the grade directly.
人家殷楠直接跳级了
She was admitted to the university in advance.
提前高考考上了西科大
Feel sorry for Xiaoyu.
那小鱼太可怜了
What are you talking about?
你们在说什么
Nothing.
什么都没说
Ah.
哎
There is no action without consequence.
有因必有果
Karma is a bitch.
天道好轮回
If she hadn't forced me,
若不是她苦苦相逼
I wouldn't have become
我也不会落到
what I am now.
今天这副田地
Come on, Xiaoyu.
小鱼加油
Win for sure, Xiaoyu.
小鱼必胜
Come on.
加油
Enjoy yourself.
都赶紧吃吧
We'll train later.
一会儿赶紧训练
Please prepare for the debate and return to the classroom quickly.
急速备战 速回教室
My fellow debater, since you have given
对方辩友既然给出了
a series of...
一系列
Friends
同志们
The fact that Thanos wears gloves
左右手
on both hands
都戴着手套的灭霸
is not enough to describe
都不足以形容
our opponent's horror.
我们对手的可怕
Qiu Lingyan
秋凌烟
used to be the best debater in the district
曾经在高中时期
for three consecutive years
蝉联过三次
during her high school years.
区最佳辩手
She is good at using logic rings to attack opponents.
擅长逻辑环进攻
Her defensive counter-attack is also very prominent.
防守反击也非常突出
This boy is called Ding Li.
这个男生 叫丁力
He is the fourth debater.
四辩
He is very good at grasping the key points.
抓点非常准
It is said that his debate style
辩风据说是
is a bit unconventional.
有点剑走偏锋
Xiaoyu, Nan Bei
接下来这两位
I heard that these next two
小鱼 南北
are your old friends.
听说是你们的故人
Please introduce them.
就由你们来介绍一下吧
In high school,
高中时候
everyone called Yin Nan the Great Devil.
大家都管殷楠叫大魔王
I don't think so anyway.
反正我是没觉得
How's her ranking?
那战绩怎么样
She luckily won a championship
高一的时候
in her first year of high school.
运气好拿到个冠军
Xiaoyu was the runner-up.
小鱼是亚军
She was also lucky in her sophomore year of high school.
高二时候运气也挺好的
She was still the runner-up.
她还是亚军
What about Liu Yanze?
那刘彦泽呢
Liu Yanze
刘彦泽
is known as Invincible Asia in Dongzhou.
号称东州市东方不败
Hum.
哼
I think they are just more alike in gender.
我看也就是性别比较像
That means
那也就是说
neither of them has ever lost.
他们俩都没输过呗
Soon.
快了
Ah.
哎
Liu Yanze is so good.
刘彦泽这么厉害啊
I have such a good taste.
姐们儿眼光真好
Now is the critical moment.
大敌当前了 姐们儿
Please stop thinking about falling in love.
把你的恋爱脑收一收吧
I also get their record last year
我也从李主任那儿
from Mr. Li.
拿到了他们去年的战绩
25 wins and 0 loss.
二十五胜 零败
Nine withdrawals.
九次退赛
Look, friends.
看到没有 同志们
That's what they are.
他们就是这样的人
They only dare to compete against people who are inferior to them.
专挑软柿子捏
They flinch when they meet someone better than them.
打不过就跑
We don't have to be afraid of them at all.
咱们根本不用怕他们
The reason for nine withdrawals
那九次退赛
is that their opponents thought they were too strong,
是对方嫌他们太强
so they withdrew voluntarily.
主动退赛
We have nothing to fear.
那我们也不用怕
Even
万一我们
a blind squirrel
我们瞎猫
can find nuts.
碰上死耗子呢我们
They're not nuts.
他们又不是死耗子
What are you doing?
你们干嘛呢
Stop chatting.
在这儿瞎聊什么呢
Ah.
啊
Time is short and tasks are numerous.
时间紧 任务重
Let's train right now.
还不赶紧练起来
Oh.
哟
You're good.
不错呀
Why are you
你什么时候
so keen on the competition?
对比赛这么上心了
I can't
那我不得
lose face in front of my Prince Charming.
在男神面前不能丢脸嘛
I'll win him over.
一举拿下他
I'll beat him with strength.
用实力战胜男神
Right.
对
I'm going to rely on this game
就要靠这场比赛
to let Liu Yanze know
让刘彦泽知道知道
who the Dad is.
谁是爸爸
Let Yin Nan know
让殷楠知道知道
who the Mom is.
谁是妈妈
Well, I'm also encouraged.
好 我也燃起来了
Friends
这样 同志们
Let's
咱们现在就
make a plan now.
制定作战计划
OK.
整
Come on.
开始
Finally.
大功告成
From 7 a.m.
从早上七点
to 12 p.m.,
到晚上十二点
minus the time to eat and sleep,
刨去吃饭和睡觉的时间
we need to train intensively
要十二个小时
for 12 hours.
的高强度训练
The training content includes
训练内容包括
voice,
语音语态
logical inertia,
逻辑惯性
on-the-spot reaction,
临场反应
watching of classic events,
经典赛事观摩
review of competitions
还有比赛复盘
and others.
等多个环节
How about it?
怎么样
Not bad, right?
不错吧
En.
嗯
It's good that you can stick to it.
能坚持下来就不错
Sa
撒哥
You're underestimating us.
你也太小瞧我们了吧
I think this amount of training
这点训练量
is just so so for us.
我感觉还是不在话下的
Hao, right?
是不是 小好姐
I really wanna believe you.
我是很想相信你们
But
但是
from what I know about you,
以我对你们的了解来看
I think it's a little impossible.
我觉得有点不可能
I set my alarm
我现在就定闹钟
at 6:00 a.m. now.
早上六点
All right.
行了吧
It's like we don't know
搞得好像大家不知道
how you spend your day.
你一天是怎么过的似的
How do I spend?
我怎么过的
The alarm clock goes off at six o'clock.
闹钟 六点钟就响了
From the moment
从睁开眼睛
he opens his eyes,
的那一刻开始
the only thing that moves
这货全身上下
all over his body
唯一会动的
is his thumb.
就是大拇指
This state
这种状态
lasts until ten o'clock in the evening.
一直持续到晚上十点钟
He actually
竟然试着
watches TikTok to fall asleep.
刷抖音刷到了睡着
When he wakes up,
醒来之后
a new day begins.
新的一天开始了
Look.
看到了吧
This is his day.
这就是他的一天
I don't even bother to talk about you.
我都懒得说你
You think you're good?
你以为你是什么样的
What about me?
我怎么着
You spend the morning in a recurring tangle of
上午 你在起床
getting up
和不起床
and not getting up.
的反复纠结中度过
At noon,
中午呢
hunger prompts you
饥饿促使你
to start a new day.
开启了新的一天
But the sun
但是阳光
blocks your view of TV series.
阻碍了你刷剧的视线
So you prepare snacks
于是你摆好零食
and drinks,
备好饮水
hide in the curtains,
躲进窗帘里
open the video website
打开视频网站
and continue
开启了又丧
watching TV dramas
又梦幻的刷剧生活
until you fall asleep.
直到睡着
This is her day.
这就是她的一天
Ah.
哎
Look.
看看
Do they look like old friends
像不像认识三十年的
who have known each other for 30 years
同窗故友
complaining about each other here?
在这儿吐槽呢
Dango, please don't waste the picture,
团子 你别浪费画面了
okay?
行吗
It's your day
把我的甜宠剧
to change my TV series
换成你淘宝
into your Taobao.
就是你的一天了
What are you watching?
看什么呢你
I'm shopping online.
买东西呀
What do you wanna buy?
你要买什么
You like this lipstick?
你也看这口红色号
I also like this lipstick.
我也看这口红来着
Buy it.
买啊
I still need to think about it.
我还得纠结一会儿
What if this lipstick
万一这口红色号
doesn't suit me?
不适合我
If you like it, buy it.
喜欢就买啊
Don't think about it.
纠结什么
Why do you
平时训练那么辛苦
train so hard?
为什么
Buy it.
买啊
I wanna defeat Yin Nan.
我为了打败殷楠
You think too much.
磨磨唧唧磨磨唧唧的
If you like it but you don't buy it,
喜欢都不买
how can you beat her?
你拿什么打败她
Buy it.
买啊
Please calm down, don't...
你先冷静一下 别着
Please don't suppress yourself.
不要压抑自己的天性
Buy it.
买呀
Please be nice to yourself.
对自己好一点
Please reward yourself. Buy it.
奖励一下自己 买呀
OK.
我买
So I'll buy one, too.
那我也买一支
So we both have it.
我们两个人闺蜜色
But don't worry, Hao.
不过 小好姐 你放心
In order to beat Western University of Science and Technology,
为了打倒西科大
and preserve
为了保住
our beautiful home,
我们美丽的家园
I will definitely quit watching TV shows,
我一定会戒掉甜宠剧
TikTok,
戒抖音
and Taobao.
戒淘宝
Well.
好
Let's take a five-minute break
那我们休息五分钟
and then start training.
开始训练
Hum.
啊
Hao
不是 小好姐
Making plans over the past few days
这几天制定计划
has killed
浪费了我
all my brain cells.
所有脑细胞了
I need a rest.
歇会儿 歇会儿
Hao, or we'll get up early
小好姐 要不然明天早上
tomorrow morning.
我们早点起来
Please don't train today.
哎呀 今天就算了吧
All right.
好吧
Please go to bed early today.
那今天早点休息
Let's start training
明天早上七点钟
at seven o'clock tomorrow morning.
开始训练
Yes, madam.
是的 长官
Hao, what's the matter?
小好姐 怎么了
All auditoriums for competition
比赛用的大礼堂
have been lent out.
全部都借出去了
Even all large classrooms
连大教室
have been arranged.
也都全部安排出去了
Our promotional videos
那咱们的宣发视频
have been released.
都发出去了
How humiliating
到时候要是个小教室
if the location is a small classroom by then.
多丢人啊
It doesn't matter.
没事
Let me ask Mr. Li again.
我再问问李主任吧
There's the spare auditorium
北门还有一个
at the north entrance.
备用的大礼堂呢
The spare auditorium at the north entrance?
北门的大礼堂
I heard it's haunted.
传言说那儿闹鬼呀
It's not that dramatic.
没那么夸张
I've held events there.
我在那儿搞过活动
There's just old equipment,
也就是设备陈旧了一点
air leak in winter
冬天漏风
and rain leak in summer.
夏天漏雨什么的
It's not that scary.
没那么吓人
Hello, FlashEx.
您好 闪送
Coming.
来了
Thank you.
谢谢啊
Dango, what do you buy again?
团子 你又买什么了
Good stuff.
好东西
Xiaoyu
小鱼
Sa
小撒老师
And mine.
还有我的呀
Yes.
嗯
From now on,
从现在起
no one can use the cell phone as an excuse
谁也不能拿手机没电
to forget the training time because it is dying.
忘记训练时间为借口了
From now on,
从今以后
we should
我们都要以
take the time of this watch as the standard.
这块表的时间为准
Well.
好
From now on,
从现在开始
let's
就让我们以
get the competition back
每小时为单位
by the hour.
找回比赛状态
By the minute.
以分钟算
By the second.
得以秒算
Yes.
嗯
Come on.
加油
I can see
一看大家昨天晚上
that you didn't sleep well last night.
就没有休息好吧
You too.
你也是吧
You must have stayed up late
一定是昨天晚上
to read the material again last night.
又熬夜看资料了
You're amazing.
真棒 了不起
You too.
你也是 你也是
Let me give you the thumbs-up.
给你们两个点赞
In that case,
那既然如此
let's get started.
让我们赶紧开始吧
Who should we start with?
从谁先开始呢
Nan Bei
南北
Look.
你看
He goes to the left and is touched.
走到左边给碰到了
Here he comes again.
又 又来了 又来了
He...
这货 这
What are you watching?
看什么呢
Look, Dog-headed Brother updates the video.
狗头哥更新了 你看
He is performing a lion dance
正在寝室用那个
in his dorm room
哈士奇枕头当那个头
with that husky pillow as his head.
舞狮在这儿
Ah.
哎
Great.
厉害
You also have
这枕头
this pillow.
你不也有吗
Hum.
那个
Ladies first.
女士优先
Either of you can start.
你们两个谁先说都行
Let me add to that.
我来补充好吧
Xiaoyu
小鱼
You must have a lot of thoughts
你一定有很多想法
to say.
已经要喷薄而出了
Come on.
来 来来来
You first.
你先来
Xiaoyu, let's watch the TV series together.
鱼 过来看剧啊
In preparation for next week's debate competition,
为了备战下周的辩论赛
I have vowed
我已经发誓
to abstain from all recreational activities.
戒除一切娱乐活动
Oh.
哦
It is the century competition
就是你们和西科大那场
between you and Western University of Science and Technology,
号称代表了
which claims to represent the pinnacle
中国现代华语辩论
of modern Chinese debate in China.
巅峰水平的世纪约战
How do you know that?
你怎么知道
Now the whole university is spreading it.
现在全学校都传开了呀
Xiaoyu
姐妹
You are now the heroine
你现在就是代表
representing DUFE.
东财出征的英雄
I'm with you.
我支持你
What's wrong?
怎么了
Ah.
啊
It's okay.
没事 没事
You should
你那个啥
make full preparations for the competition first.
你先好好准备
Ah.
哎呀
How did this happen?
怎么会这样啊
Qincai is mine.
芹菜是我的
No, she's mine.
不 是我的
So what?
那又怎么样
You guys stop fighting.
你们不要再打了
Stop fighting.
不要再打了
Dango
团子
Or you first.
要不然你先吧
I'll sort out my thoughts.
我整理一下思绪
I'll sort out
等一下整理一下
your words later.
你的话就可以了
Why are we
我们什么时候
so humble?
变得这么谦让了
Nan Bei
南北
Ah.
诶
Don't you always have trouble holding your words?
你不是一向憋不住话吗
You first.
你先来吧
It's okay.
没事
You both can.
你们两个都行
You first.
你们先 你们先
Ah.
诶
Don't be polite to us.
别跟我们客气嘛
Come on.
来嘛
You first.
你来吧
No.
不不不
If you go on like this,
你要再这样继续下去
I have reason to believe
我可就有理由相信
that you didn't read the information
昨天晚上
last night.
没有看资料了哟
It would not be too much
那我要是怀疑你
for me to suspect
昨天晚上
that you did not prepare anything
什么都没有准备
last night, right?
也不算过分了吧
Why do you two say that?
瞧你们两个说的
It's as if none of us
就好像我们
has prepared the information
谁都没有准备资料
and none of us wants to start first.
谁都不愿起头一样
Nan Bei, you must
南北昨天晚上
have watched TikTok all night last night.
刷一晚上抖音吧你
You must have watched TV shows again.
你肯定又追剧了吧
You both are too much.
你们两个都太过分了
I just shop for daily necessities.
我也就刷刷日用品
Strictly speaking,
这个严格意义
this is not an entertainment.
上说是不算的
Why?
怎么 什么你
We have an appointment to train together.
我们约好的一块训练的
You don't keep your word.
你们都没有准
Hao
小好
How is the preparation for the competition going?
比赛准备得怎么样了
They are all working very hard
大家都铆足了劲
and enthusiastically to prepare for the competition.
正在热火朝天地准备呢
What's going on?
我怎么 怎么回事
I'm right.
我怎么了
Great.
好
What is your business?
你找我有什么事吗
Mr. Li
是这样的 李主任
Now
就是现在
the auditoriums for competition
学校比赛用的礼堂
have been lent out.
都已经借完了
I would like to ask
我想问一下
who is managing
北门的那个备用礼堂
the spare auditorium at the north gate.
现在是谁在管理呀
The spare auditorium at the north gate?
北门那个礼堂
Let me take a look.
我看一下啊
Take a look.
看一下
Yes, it's this.
对 是这个
This is the clubroom
给这个夕阳红社团
of Sunset Club.
当社团教室了
Sunset Club?
夕阳红社团
Look.
你看
This is the signature of the person in charge.
还有这个负责人的签字
Mr. Li
那李主任
I'd like to ask about
我想问一问
the use of this auditorium.
这个礼堂的使用情况
I'd like to talk to their club about
看看能不能跟他们社团
whether we can use it together.
商量一下一起用
You mean
你的意思是
to find this person in charge?
找这个负责人吗
Yes.
嗯
I have to remind you
我可得提醒你一下啊
that if you wanna look for help from this person,
你要找这个人帮忙
you must be
你可要做好
fully prepared mentally.
充分的心理准备啊
Ah.
哎
Excuse me, are you Ma Nan?
请问是马楠学长吗
Yes, I'm.
正是敝人
Who are you?
你是
Hello.
学长 你好
I'm Tao Hao from the Students' Union.
我是学生会的陶好
We both serve in the Students' Union.
我们都在学生会任职
But I never
只是从来没有
met you at the student union.
在学生会见过你
This is normal.
正常
I don't stay there very often.
我不常在那儿待的
Ma Nan
学长 是这样的
I come to see you this time
我这次来找你
because my debate team
是因为我所在的辩论队
wants to borrow the auditorium
想借用学校的礼堂
to play a game.
打一场比赛
I heard from Mr. Li
我听李主任说
that it is now used
现在是一个叫
by a club called Sunset Club,
夕阳红的社团在用
right?
是吗
Right.
哦 是的
Can you
那可不可以
lend it to us?
借我们用一下
I don't think so.
应该不行吧
Sunset Club has many activities.
夕阳红社团活动很多的
Ma Nan
学长
This competition
这个比赛
is very important for us.
对我们来说很重要
Is there any other way...
那有没有别的办法
Once upon a time,
在很久很久以前
Alexander the Great,
马其顿国王
king of Macedonia,
亚历山大大帝
visited the philosopher Diogenes
过科忒林市的时候
when he was passing through Corinth.
拜访哲学家第欧根尼
He then asked Diogenes.
他就问第欧根尼
He said, Mr. Diogenes,
他说第欧根尼先生
whatever you want
不管你要什么东西
I can give you.
我都能给你
Guess what Diogenes answered.
你猜第欧根尼说什么
Get out of the way, please.
请你让开一点
You're blocking my sunlight.
你挡到我的阳光了
So you know it.
你知道啊
I think that if you don't know,
我还想着你要不知道
it'll work better if I say it.
我说出来效果会更好
You're blocking my sunlight.
你 你挡着我晒太阳了
I get it.
学长 我懂
I'm Diogenes.
我是第欧根尼
You're Alexander.
你是亚历山大
I'm being sarcastic, you know?
就是借古讽今你懂吗
So...
所以
Ma Nan
马楠学长 要不这样吧
Please give me the contact
你直接把夕阳红社团的
of Sunset Club directly.
联系方式给我
I'll contact them myself.
我自己去跟他们对接
The contact of Sunset Club
学生会的记录本上
is in
就有他们
the student union's record book.
夕阳红社团的联系方式
No need for that.
不用了
They are too busy
他们太忙了
and probably don't have time.
估计也没那个时间
Here's the deal.
这样吧
You wanna
你们不是想
borrow the auditorium for one day.
借学校礼堂一天嘛
You write an application
你去写个申请材料
and give it to me.
交给我
Then I hand it over to the superiors.
我往上面递一下
If they agree,
如果他们同意了
I'll lend you the classroom key.
我就把教室钥匙借给你
Okay, thanks.
好 谢谢学长
Oh.
哦
Please continue
那就不打扰
to enjoy the sunshine.
您享受阳光了
Mr. Diogenes
第欧根尼先生
It seems we
看来大家都
are all in bad shape.
没什么状态呀
Let's recite
咱们背背
the article of the brain box to boost our energy.
大神的国文提提气
Come on.
来吧
Let's recite this paragraph.
那就这段吧
When everyone
当大家都在背稿
is reciting the manuscript
搞得天衣无缝
to be perfect,
精雕细琢时
I will advise you to leave.
我会劝你即席
In this way,
如此一来
your usual language,
你平时的用语
occasional stuttering,
偶尔的结巴
incoherent words under excitement
激动下的词不达意
are all weapons instead.
反而一样一样都是武器
When everyone
当大家都是即席
is improvising
搞得朴拙无华
imperfectly,
原形毕露时
I advise you to recite the manuscript.
我劝你背稿
At this point,
此时
At this point, the words under excitement,
此时 你激动下的用词
the smooth rhythm,
流畅的节奏
the sentences
连带排比押韵
with parallelism and rhyme
的段子就会
become conspicuous.
异军突起 鹤立鸡群
I really like this paragraph.
我超爱这段
I'm also right.
我也说得通透
Ah.
哎
Convention.
老规矩
Gentlemen's agreement.
君子协议
All entertainment is prohibited
比赛之前戒除
prior to the competition.
一切娱乐消遣
Let's monitor each other.
互相监督
The stricter the punishment system is,
惩罚制度
the better it is.
越狠越好
Deal.
成交
Ma Nan
学长
All the documents
所有的文件
have been signed by the teacher.
老师都已经签好字了
Now you can
你现在可以把
give me the contact
夕阳红社团的
of the president of Sunset Club.
社长的联系方式给我了
Don't bother.
不用麻烦你
I can contact him myself.
我自己跟他联系就好
I've already contacted them.
我已经跟他们联系好了
They allow
他们同意
you to use the spare auditorium.
你使用备用礼堂
Really?
真的
Yes.
嗯
Then I'll go to the auditorium now.
那我现在去礼堂看看
But you may not be able to get in now.
不过你现在可能进不去
Why?
为什么
Because Sunset Club
因为夕阳红社团
lost the key.
把钥匙给弄丢了
They said they'd let me know
他们说如果找到的话
if they found it.
会告诉我
Can they find it?
这能找到吗
Maybe one day.
快的话一天
Maybe more than ten days.
慢的话十天半个月吧
To sum up,
综上所述
hypothesis of rational man
理性人假设
is less adaptable
在现代社会中
in modern society.
适应性更低
How long?
多少
Three minutes and 26 seconds.
三分二十六秒
Not bad.
不错呀
How many arguments do I have?
我有几个论点
Three big arguments.
三个大论点
Five sub-arguments.
五个分论点
There are still two arguments that lack supporting evidence.
还有两个论点缺乏论据
I did well.
表现不错嘛
I think we don't
感觉咱们想看手机
wanna play with our phones.
那个劲过去了
After we calm down,
静下心以后
we get no less happiness from preparing for the debate
备战获得的快乐感
than watching dramas.
一点不比看剧少
That's great.
太好了
We get through this
我们可算是一块
together.
跨过了这道坎了
Thank you, Nan Bei.
谢谢你啊 南北
Thank you.
谢谢你
I'll buy something to drink.
我去买点喝的
What would you like to drink?
你喝什么吗
Lemon tea.
柠檬茶
OK.
好
Qincai, let me explain.
芹菜 你听我解释
I don't wanna hear it.
不听
Qincai
芹菜
Things are not
事情不是你
what you think.
想象的那样子
I don't wanna hear it.
我不听 我不听 我不听
Qincai
芹菜
Qincai, please don't go.
芹菜 你别走
Be careful.
小心
Qincai
芹菜
Oh, my God.
我的天哪
Is it good?
好看吗
Nan Bei, why are you here?
南北 你怎么来了
How could you cheat me?
你怎么可以欺骗我
Let me explain.
我可以解释
Explain what?
解释什么解释
I don't wanna hear it.
我不听
You want.
你听
Hello, I'm here.
喂 师傅 我到楼下了
I see you.
我看到你了
Nan Bei
南北
I knew
认识这货的第一天
it was doomed love
我就知道
the first day I met her.
这是一份孽缘
Hello.
同学 同学
What's wrong with you?
你什么情况
I just had surgery on my heart.
心脏刚做过手术
The doctor said I was not allowed to exercise strenuously.
医生说不让剧烈运动
You're overdoing it.
你这也太夸张了吧
Hello.
同学
What's wrong with you?
你怎么了
I seem to be suffering from heatstroke.
我好像有点中暑
Heatstroke?
中暑
I'm dizzy, thirsty and a little nauseous.
头晕 口渴 有点恶心
Nauseous?
恶心
You pretend well.
你这演得好啊
Next.
下一位
I'm coming.
来了
What's wrong with you?
哪儿不舒服
Miss
老师
I fainted
我刚才站着站着
when I was standing just now.
就晕倒了
I'm dizzy,
头晕
thirsty
口渴
and a little nauseous.
犯恶心
Am I suffering from heatstroke?
我是不是中暑了
21 pretenders
今天早上已经来了
have come this morning.
二十一个装病的了
You're the 22nd.
你是第二十二个
Ah.
啊
I'm the 22nd.
我是第二十二个
Miss
老师
What's wrong with you?
你又怎么了
I'm dizzy, thirsty
我有点头晕 口渴
and a little nauseous.
还有点犯恶心
She's the 23rd.
第二十三个
It's no use
两位同学
pretending to be ill.
装病是没有用的
I'm really sick.
我是真的
I'm really sick, too.
我 我也是真的
We are all really sick.
我们都是真的
Do you know this?
这个认识吗
Now I give you two choices,
现在给你们两条路
either go out by yourself
要么你们自己出去
or take your temperature
要么量完体温
and send you to the class teacher.
送你们去见班主任
Ah.
哎 哎
I'm well.
好了
What are you doing?
你干嘛
I feel bad.
我难受
Let's stick to it.
我们再坚持坚持
I really feel bad.
我是真难受
Nothing is impossible
世上无难事
to a willing mind.
只怕有心人
It's okay.
没事
Let's do some trauma next time.
咱们下次整点外伤
Trauma is realistic.
外伤逼真
I really feel bad.
大哥 我是真不行了
All right. You still pretend
行了 你这么久还没
after all this time?
还没出戏呢
But you pretend well.
不过你这挺专业
I should learn from you.
值得我学习
I'll be like you next time.
下次我也像你这样
Ah.
哎
Are you all right?
你没事吧
Someone faints here.
有人晕倒了
Ah.
哎
Come around?
醒了
I take a small part of the blame
害你输液
for letting you have an infusion.
我占小部分责任
But you,
但你说你也是
as a contemporary woman,
你作为当代女性
should be brave enough
你就应该
to express yourself.
勇敢地表达自己
How can you
站在我身后
stand behind me
唯唯诺诺的算
so timidly?
怎么回事啊
Next time,
下回啊
you should stand in front of me.
你就站在我前面
If you're sick, you must speak up.
有病就得大声说出来
Are you done?
你这人有完没完啊
I sacrificed myself
为了在你休克之前
to get you to the infirmary
给你送到医务室
before you went into shock.
舍身取义了一把
It was my fault to pretend to be sick before.
之前装病那事是我不对
Let's call it even now.
咱俩扯平了
You don't look
你这人看着
very clever,
智商就不太高
and you talk so much.
嘴还怎么那么碎啊
You should debate
你有这个本事
if you have this ability.
打辩论多好
You should know that our university
知道咱们学校
has a debate team.
有辩论队吧
I'm Nan Bei,
我呀
the rising star
就是东财大辩论队
of the debate team of DUFE.
冉冉升起的新星 南北
I'm Mu Xiaoyu,
牧小鱼
the future of the debate team of DUFE.
东财大辩论队的未来
Nan Bei
南北
You come around.
你醒了
That's ok.
没事
I do think of some
我这倒是想起了一些
old things.
以前的事
You scared me.
吓死我了
Tao Hao, you come just in time.
陶好 你来得太及时了
I suspected
我之前就怀疑
that Sunset Club
夕阳红社团
used the public resources of the university privately.
私用学校公共资源
Now it's true.
现在一查果然是这样
I looked into it.
学长 我查过了
In the archives,
学校档案里
the president of Sunset Club
夕阳红社团的团长
is Li Jinjiao,
叫李金角
and the member is Wang Yinjiao.
团员叫王银角
You made
这一切
all this up.
都是学长你编的吧
I initially wanted to call them
我本来想叫
Benboerba and Baboerben.
奔波儿灞和灞波儿奔的
I later gave up
后来觉得
when I thought they were easy to see through.
容易被识破就放弃了
I won't report these
这些
to the university for the time being.
我暂时不会上报给校方
I'll give you one day
我给你一天时间
to clean up this place.
把这里都清理干净
One day?
一天
Yes.
嗯
This workload is a bit heavy.
这工作量有点大吧
So I suggest
所以我建议
you clean it up
学长从现在开始
from now on.
就清理吧
Thank you, Ma Nan.
辛苦了 马楠学长
Would you like to?
你愿意吗
I do.
我愿意
What to do?
怎么办
I don't even know
我都不知道
if Qincai is dead.
芹菜死了没有
All right.
好了啊
When the competition is over,
等打完比赛
I'll watch the replay with you.
陪你看重播
Excuse me.
打 打扰了
Dango
团子
Nan Bei and I have made up our minds
我跟南北下定决心
to delete Tik Tok and videos
删除了彼此
from each other's phones.
手机里的抖音和视频
Really?
真的
Great.
太好了
I've also deleted Taobao.
我也删除了淘宝
Friends
同志们
There is a piece of wonderful news.
特大喜讯
We can use
我们可以用
the spare auditorium for the competition.
备用礼堂进行比赛了
Really?
真假的
Yes.
真的呀
I know
我就知道嘛
anything can be done
有小好姐出马
with Hao.
肯定什么事都能办成
We also successfully
我们也成功
quit cell phone dependence.
戒掉了手机依赖症
Really, friends?
是吗 同志们
The darkness has passed.
黑暗已经过去
The dawn is not far away.
黎明不会遥远
Let's forget about the pain
让我们一扫阴霾
and prepare for the competition.
全力备战
Let's go.
好 干活
Dango, you're great.
我们小团子这么棒啊
You correct your shortcomings immediately.
毛病说改就改
Nan Bei and I
我跟南北
are not as good as you.
都没你这么棒呢
There's nothing I can do.
我也没办法了
I can't keep buying.
不能一直买买买
I'm also out of money.
也没钱了
It's better not to buy.
不买也好
Save you regret it.
省得剁团子的爪爪了
You can save money
以后少喝两杯奶茶
by drinking fewer cups of milk tea.
就出来了啊
Hello.
哥们
Ah.
啊
These shoes are very popular.
这鞋挺火啊
Not bad.
凑合吧
You also like sneakers?
你也喜欢球鞋啊
Yes.
嗯
What brands and styles
有没有中意的品牌
do you like?
跟款式啊
I can get them all.
我都能搞得到
But you have to add some money
就是得加点钱
for me to make money.
那个赚点辛苦钱
You wanna make money.
你要赚钱
Why do you come here in line?
你跑这儿排队干嘛
This pair of AJ is a replica version,
这双AJ是复刻版
which is easy to depreciate.
容易贬值
And the main customers of this pair of shoes
而且这双鞋
are students.
主打客户是学生
They can wait a few more months.
他完全可以多等几个月
They can wait until the shoes are 50% off and 30% off.
等五折七折的时候再买
Apple next door launches new products today.
隔壁苹果今天新货首发
This is the rigid demand.
这才是刚需啊 兄弟
Thanks.
谢了啊
Ah.
哎
Hum.
嗯
Hello.
小伙子
Why are you sighing?
叹什么气啊
Maybe what he wants is not a pair of shoes
也许他要的不是一双鞋
but care.
而是关心
For example,
比如啊
you should cook noodles
这深更半夜的
for him who stays up late to review
给熬夜复习的他
late at night.
亲手煮碗面
Oh.
哦
I got it.
我明白了
Thanks.
谢谢你啊 小伙子
You're welcome.
没事 阿姨
I'll be right back.
我这就回去
Hello.
小伙子
What's wrong?
干啥
You like to play basketball, right?
喜欢打篮球是吧
Just so so.
一般
Let me tell you
哥哥告诉你一些人生中
some of the most important things in life.
至关重要的道理吧
What?
啥道理啊
Do you know
知道苏格拉底
what Socrates said?
怎么说的吗
I don't know.
咋说的
Know yourself.
认清自己
Do you know
知道古斯塔夫·勒庞
what Gustave Le Bon said?
怎么说的
I don't know.
咋说的
Know the crowd.
认清乌合之众
I got it.
我明白了 我明白了
Thanks.
谢谢哥 谢谢哥
You're welcome.
没事 真没事
Hello.
兄弟
I think you're a talent.
我觉得你特有才华
I'm flattered.
过奖
But now you have a problem.
但是你现在遇到一问题
What?
什么
There are at least
按你这种方式
170 people ahead.
前面保险起见
There are still two hours before the sale.
还有一百七十个人
In your way,
距离开售还有两个小时
even if you win one over in five minutes,
就算你五分钟搞定一个
you still can't buy it.
还是没戏
So?
所以呢
I suggest we cooperate.
我建议咱们合作
Excuse me.
不好意思
I'm used to fighting alone.
我习惯单打独斗
Then you convince me first.
那你先说服我吧
Right.
好
Deal.
成交
Ah.
哎
Hello.
美女